Williams, Lawrence, Papers /4310
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Lawrence Williams Papers
1958-1977
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Williams, Lawrence
/4310
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Papers (documents).
8491382
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, August 13, 2014
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, February 28, 2019
Biographical / Historical
In 1952, Professor Williams graduated cum laude from Tufts University. He received his Masters Degree in 1954 from the University Illinois. In 1960, he earned a PhD in psychology from the University of Michigan. Professor Williams served in the U.S. Army from 1954-56, and
worked as a research psychologist. In 1961 he came to Cornell University as an assistant professor, and became a full professor in 1969. When he retired in 1999, his colleagues awarded him an emeritus professorship.
During his long career, Professor Williams served for a period as chairman of the Department of Organizational Behavior and for 25 years was the director of graduate studies for the school of Industrial and Labor Relations. He served on the committees of over 250 graduate students and was chairman for more than 70 students.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections:
Williams, Lawrence
8491382
- A, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Recruiting Comm., 1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Lawrence Williams; Memos, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- S., 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- T., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- U., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- W., 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- R., 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Q, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- P, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Graduate Committee '64-'67, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Graduate Assistants '62-'67, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- G, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Grad. Comm.: Recent Data: 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Graduate Committee - 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- H., 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- I, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Research Publications '62 and '66, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- J, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- K, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- L, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- M, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- F, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Q, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- N, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Extension Conference - April 11, 1962 Wohlking, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- B, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- D, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Coel Studies, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- C, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Grad. Faculty - 66-67, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Info. Sent to Grad. Students - Falls, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Fulbright, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Ad Hoc Committee IRIS, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Int'l Student Affairs, 1969-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- H., 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Human Affairs Program, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- J-K, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- L (1 of 2), 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Leaksonen, Oiva, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Library Administrator's Dev. Program University of Maryland July, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- File Latin American Program, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- L (2 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Job Applications March, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Administrative Conference Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Lawrence Williams Memos, 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lawrence Williams Memos, 1971-1976 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Lawrence Williams; Bibliographies and Seminars, 1961-1969 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Andean Studies, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Misc. Documents, 1969-1974 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Center for Improvement of Undergraduate Education, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Corning Area Survey Center, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Library Administration Develop. Program August 1974, 1972-1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- New York Hospital - 10/71, 1969-1973 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Lyman Porter, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Publication Agreement, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- SFM Fall Classes 1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Research + Pub 4/28, 1967-1970 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Department Exams - Fall 1974 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Library Administrators Development Prog. May 29, 1975, 1967-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- O.B. Exams. Fall 1974 Closed Book and Open Book Candidates 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 and 6, 1963-1972 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Center for Improvement of Undergraduate Education, 1966-1970 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Memorandums, 1968-1973 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- O.B. Department Sept. 1969 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Rural Sociology, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Organizational Behavior Sept. '67, 1967-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Graduate Committee - Fall '62, 1962-1967 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Org. Beh., 1958-1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Encyclopedia Britannica, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Everett C. Hughes Chapter, 1965-1968 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- OMAT Program 1 of 3, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- OMAT Program 2 of 3, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- OMAT Program 3 of 3, 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- OMAT Program 3 of 3, 1965-1969 (Box 5, Folder 10)